<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Other on Yerbol Aussat</title>
    <link>http://yerbolaussat.github.io/tags/other/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Other on Yerbol Aussat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://yerbolaussat.github.io/tags/other/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sudoku puzzle as a constraint satisfaction problem</title>
      <link>http://yerbolaussat.github.io/project/sudoku-solver/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yerbolaussat.github.io/project/sudoku-solver/</guid>
      <description>See Code
See Analysis
Java implementation of a bot that solves Sudoku puzzles.
The algorithm implements the backtracking search algorithm with forward checking and three heuristics:
 Minimum remaining values heuristic Minimum degree heuristic Least constraining value heuristic  Sudoku Puzzle is modeled as a Constraint Satisfaction Problem (CSP) as follows:
Variables: 81 variables, one for each square / cell
Domains: Empty squares have domain {1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9} and the prefilled squares have a domain consisting of a single value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course status tracker</title>
      <link>http://yerbolaussat.github.io/project/track-courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yerbolaussat.github.io/project/track-courses/</guid>
      <description>See Code
This program uses Selenium Webdriver to automate checking course status on UWaterloo&amp;rsquo;s Quest portal. Whenever the course of interest becomes available, the program notifies a user.
Currently headless PhantomJS driver and browser-based ChromeDrive are supported.
TO-DO: Implement course status inquiries from Quest portal with Selenium Webdriver Implement notifications when a course opens
 Send a text message / email to the user once the course is open Automatically register a user for a course</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calendar App (OOD)</title>
      <link>http://yerbolaussat.github.io/project/ood_calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yerbolaussat.github.io/project/ood_calendar/</guid>
      <description>See Code</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Storage and Retrieval System</title>
      <link>http://yerbolaussat.github.io/project/go-getters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yerbolaussat.github.io/project/go-getters/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Balance Car</title>
      <link>http://yerbolaussat.github.io/project/hot-wheelz/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yerbolaussat.github.io/project/hot-wheelz/</guid>
      <description>The Balance Car is a free-rolling car with a tilting balance platform mounted on top. The balance platform, controlled by a servo-motor and microcontroller, responds to both the tilt (pitch) and the longitudinal acceleration of the car so that a small object will be cradled on the platform as the car rolls down the roll-car track. A 9 degree-of-freedom inertial measurement unit (IMU) mounted on the car sends angular velocity, acceleration, and heading data to the micro-controller, which is used to calculate the pitch of the car.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic Levitation with a Floating Steel Ball</title>
      <link>http://yerbolaussat.github.io/project/magnetic-levitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yerbolaussat.github.io/project/magnetic-levitation/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitLet</title>
      <link>http://yerbolaussat.github.io/project/gitlet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yerbolaussat.github.io/project/gitlet/</guid>
      <description>See Code
A Version Control System, inspired by Git. Designed in Java.
This Version Control System mimics some of the basic features of the popular version control system Git, only smaller ofcourse. For the uninitiated, a version control system helps you save snapshots of your files at different points in time. That way, if you mess them up later, you can return to earlier versions.
Gitlet supports operations such as staging/unstaging files, merging, removing, rebasing and interactively rebasing branches.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>